hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation playlist so
continuing with our topic on test
automation obstacles let's look at our
next obstacle which is called future
Christmas now this is related to a date
format and here what we need to do is we
need to calculate on which day Christmas
25 December falls in the next 2 years
which means after two years what day
would Christmas fall on it could be a
Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday or
Friday right so we have to write it as a
word okay so in this Christmas is near
and there is a text box enter the day so
here we need to write the day and uh if
we calculate then the ch Christmas after
2 years would fall on a Friday okay so
that's basically the answer and that
will solve the obstacle but we need to
do this using tosa so let's see how we
can achieve this particular automation
using the date
Expressions so coming back to our TSA
workspace uh the first step is to get
that uh module which contains that text
box so I'm going to scan this
quickly so here I'm going to just select
the text box uh that is all uh what we
need and I will also rename the module
here and then save this and close
it okay um so that is done next uh we
need to add a test case so I'll go to
our obstacles folder and I will create
the test case here and then I'm going to
add the respective module right
here
okay so here uh we need to use some
Expressions uh which is the date
expression but we also need to find out
the day on which that particular date
falls on right so for that uh we need to
use some expression like uh the L day
okay so what it does it uh provides you
with the day according to the current
system settings okay so the result could
be a day uh which is stated in words
okay so inside this you can then put
your own date expression as given in
this particular syntax and example right
and the result would be a day so that's
what this particular expression does
okay now inside this we are going to
write the date expression and as you
know uh we can put a base date we can
put a offset and we can also put a
format but uh we don't require uh the
format in this case we just require the
base date and then we require the offset
which is uh plus two years right because
we are trying to find the date uh after
2 years right so we are going to write
this particular expression so in this uh
we are going to write the date uh so we
know that it is the Christmas so 25
December so I'm going to write 2512 and
then I'm going to write the current date
or current year right in this
2024 and then um we are going to write
the offset here which is plus 2
years right uh we will leave the format
empty because we don't want to change
the format here and then let's close
this expression and this expression okay
so that's all uh we need to do here we
just need to write the correct
expression which will provide us the
result now one way to verify this is you
can verify it right here so you can
right click on this expression and click
on translate value and uh it will
provide you with the correct value which
is Friday right and now we can use this
to enter it into the particular text
box right so uh this uh will input it
into the text box so let's go ahead and
run this now I'll change the work state
to complete it and then let's try and uh
run this in
scratchbook okay so as you can see U the
day which was Friday was entered into
the text box and the automation obstacle
was completed so you can use the
different date expr questions to
manipulate your dates based on the
requirements of your test case and then
you can run them um as per the
requirements that's all for this
particular video if you have any
questions then please leave it in the
comments if you like this video then
please subscribe to our Channel thanks
for watching and I will see you in the
next video